Barrett Flemons

Interaction Designer | Front End Developer

About

An Interaction Designer who lives for the challenge, constantly strives to learn more, and get out of my comfort zone.

The charismatic connection needed to bring teams further. I happen to love getting my hands dirty in code when not designing interfaces and experiences.

My true passion lies with the design of interactions. A small but impactful feature in a car when I was younger introduced me to the amount of thought that goes into something seemingly insignificant. I have carried this sentiment since.

Skills

| Methodology | Programs |
|---------------------------------|-------------------------------|
| Design Thinking | • Illustrator |
| • Wireframing | Photoshop |
| Information architecture | InDesign |
| Usability Testing | • After Effects |
| Prototyping | • Premiere Pro |
| • 3D Modeling | • Adobe XD |
| • Front-end Development | • Rhino 3D |
| Creative Problem Solving | • Cinema 4D |

Contact



barrettflemons@gmail.com



bflemons.com



∠89 · 828 · 0726



Burlington, Ontario, Canada

Experience

2017 · Canadian Tire - DD&L · Web Design Co-op

- Worked within a small team on maintaining Canadian Tire's e-learning platform
- · Designed and developed multiple web pages and banners, along with creating print based materials.

2017-2018 · Canadian Tire - DD&L · Web Design Contract

· Independently designed and developed digitized version of the Canadian Tire University Administrator Guide

2016 - 2018 · Freelance Designer

· Completed illustrations and UI designs for individual clients

Education

2014-2018 · Bachelor of Interaction Design

+ Certificate in Creativity and Creative Problem Solving Sheridan College Institute of Technology & Advanced Learning Oakville, Ontario

Achievements

2017 · CTU Admin Site Redesign · Canadian Tire Internship

- · Redesign of administrator website to match rebrand of Canadian Tire University
- · Analyzed current website, wireframed and mocked up potential solutions, then coded final webpages

2017 · CTU Admin Guide Digitization · Canadian Tire Internship

- · Construction of web responsive guides for administrators
- Designed print based guide, wireframed web version, coded

2017 · Usability Testing for KPDI · Usability Studies Lab

- Developed testing plan for independent client of KPDI
- · Completed a heuristic evaluation, constructed full test plan, and conducted 5 tests for the client

2017 · Data Visualization for Inovation Hub · Data Visualization 2

- · Completed a web based data visualization of Canadian housing crisis
- · Researched problem area, wireframed and mocked-up solution, illustrated and developed web site